<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Opinion on Pablo Martín</title><link>https://ervinuelas.github.io/categories/opinion/</link><description>Recent content in Opinion on Pablo Martín</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ervinuelas.github.io/categories/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Aarhus for an international CS student</title><link>https://ervinuelas.github.io/p/about-aarhus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ervinuelas.github.io/p/about-aarhus/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I am writing this post as a summary of some questions I usually get from
students who are considering coming to pursue a Master&amp;rsquo;s or Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree at Aarhus University.
I hope people can benefit from it, and get some answers to the questions we have all
asked ourselves when thinking about moving to another country to study. I will keep
updating it when I come up with new things that I consider relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything written here is my opinion and/or experiences, and I will try to avoid
writing about facts that can be easily checked with a quick internet check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="the-city-itself"&gt;The city itself
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start talking about the city. Coming from a 5 years of Bachelor in Madrid, I
didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like moving to another big city, so I only considered medium size
(less than 500k inhabitants) cities. Aarhus is the right size for me, a city you can cross
in a 30 min ride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it is also a vibrant city. Thanks to the university, a lot of young people
choose to live here (the average age is 26 wtf!). It is also due to the university
that there is a hectic international vibe. There are plenty of events for internationals,
there is always something to do during the weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding transport, there is a very punctual and frequent public transport system.
Nevertheless, people usually move around with their bikes since
there is a dense and and well preserved network of bike paths. Also, getting
a bike is quite cheap. You can get them from 500dkk (~60 eur) in the second hand
market or you can rent them from 140 dkk (~20 euro) a month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sports"&gt;Sports
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on my experience and the people around me, I think doing sports in Aarhus
is quite cheap, even when compared with Spain. I am a member of a judo club and a climbing
association, and the sum costs me around 6k dkk(~800 euro) a year. You will usually also have a gym
at your dorm or if you prefer open spaces, there are a lot of parks and green areas
where you can let go some steam by either running or going to the calisthenics zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="healthcare"&gt;Healthcare
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is universal and free, which means you don&amp;rsquo;t have to pay and you get everything you
need(nice!), except for stuff like dentists or physiotherapy sessions. Anyway, I had to make
use of it and the experience was smooth and as nice as it could have been. They took care
of me and I felt safe all the way, which I think is important when you are in
a foreign country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="su-and-working"&gt;SU and working
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Basically, if you are an EU citizen and work for at least 10/12 hours a week, you
get a grant from the state of 4k dkk (~600 euros), after taxes, every month. There are some rules
around it, but that is basically it. HUGE perk in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, you still need to get a job for it. I think landing a studies-relevant
student part time job is not difficult, if you are a CS student. Otherwise it
is not so easy, take it into account. After the first six months, all my CS
fellow international friends were able to get a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="housing"&gt;Housing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unlike in other places in Europe, getting an apartment here is quite easy and cheap.
I got mine 2 months before arriving here, through the university &lt;a class="link" href="https://studenthousingaarhus.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.
I share a kitchen with other students, but I have my own bathroom and bedroom(with furniture).
You can pay from 300 to 500, depending on your preferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the link to the place where I &lt;a class="link" href="https://kollegiekontoret.dk/en/vilh-kiers-kollegium/gallery/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
&gt;live&lt;/a&gt;,
I think the gallery represents quite faithfully how the rooms are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="life"&gt;Life
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also get questioned a lot regarding how easy it is to meet people. As I said, there is
a solid portion of the students who are international and easy to approach
since they also are new and want to make new friends. I would reccommend attending the
events promoted from the International Office, since it is an easy way to meet new people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I think most people meet their group of friends either at their dorm, at class or by joining some
sports club. Those are also the best ways to start to make some danish friends, outside
these eviroments I would say it is more difficult to approach the locals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a concept, which I think is common accross Denmark, that is the Friday
bar. Basically, every Friday, each department has a bar that is organized by
students with usually very cheap prices. It is where students usually meet for a beer,
or two, or three&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Depending of what you like, there is a Friday bar for you. Computer Science is known for being
quite chill and as a good starter of the night, whereas Medicine or BSS are more like
a proper night club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="the-university"&gt;The university
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The teaching style depends on the classes but it usually consists of a mix of
theoretical classes and then exercise classes where you apply what you
learnt in class. Depending on the subject, you might get assignments or projects,
team projects are a constant throughout the master, it is a very popular format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the exams are oral, which was a new format for me. It usually consists of
a presentation and some afterwards questions. It may seem intimidating, but you get used to it
and nowadays I actually prefer it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Aarhus to Badajoz</title><link>https://ervinuelas.github.io/p/aarhus-badajoz/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ervinuelas.github.io/p/aarhus-badajoz/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://ervinuelas.github.io/p/aarhus-badajoz/cercanias.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post From Aarhus to Badajoz" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today I once again traveled from the city where I live, Aarhus (Denmark), to my
hometown, Badajoz (Spain), to visit my loved ones and enjoy some time at home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the long hours of the trip, I usually enjoy most of it and the 14-17
hours I spend leave a lot of room for reflexions and facing my own
thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the last hours of the trip, while I was crossing the usual mediterranean
forests of Spain, I realized how lucky I am. Although it is a long trip, the mere
fact that I can combine on a sigle day at least four different types of public
transport, go through four countries and manage to travel more than 2700km makes
me realise how well coordinated our society (the european) is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overview of the journey is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Woke up at 5:00 AM, had some breakfast and headed to my nearest bus stop to
catch the 5:20 bus that dropped me at the Aarhus train station.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hopped in a train at 6:00(god, I love danish trains) and arrived to
Copenhagen&amp;rsquo;s airport at 9:35.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Right on time to catch my 11:05 flight to Madrid, a flight that arrived at
the promised time of 14:35.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then I took the regional train to Madrid train station and grabbed some lunch
on the go. Here is a picture of the beautiful architecture at this station.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The train to Badajoz left at 16:38 and is expected to arrive at 21:00.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the beauty of it is that, not only every single mean of transport arrived
on time, but also the infrastructure that surrounds each of them. For example,
when I left Aarhus at a very early hour, the coffe shop of the station was
already up a running so the average commuter can grab a coffe and start working
from the comfort of the train. Or the fact that anytime I needed to use the
bathroom there was one at a less than a minute walk (and very clean btw). Or the
variety of lunch options I had just at a 10 min walk from Madrid Atocha train
station. You get the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This make the travel so much easier and uneventful. I spent most of my time of
the time working, reading or looking through the window, activities that I would
have done anyway or that I enjoy. I don&amp;rsquo;t feel I have wasted my time today, as
it is the case when I have to drive or share a car. Those time I can spend from
2 to 4 hours just sitting and looking at a line of asphalt, hopefully with music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end there is always room for improvement, specially regarding the public
transport network in Spain of medium size cities as mine. But I think we, as a
society, should be proud of what we accomplished so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>